export const chapter = "Chapter - 9: Caste System and Reform";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [

        {
          question:
            "What were the four broad classes in the ancient Hindu community based on occupations?",
          optionA: "Brahmins, Kshatriyas, Vaishyas, and Shudras",
          optionB: "Scholars, Farmers, Traders, and Artisans",
          optionC: "Priests, Warriors, Traders, and Workers",
          correctAnswer: "C) Priests, Warriors, Traders, and Workers",
        },
        {
          question:
            "In the ancient caste system, what determined a person's occupation?",
          optionA: "Birth",
          optionB: "Personal choice",
          optionC: "Family wealth",
          correctAnswer: "B) Personal choice",
        },
        {
          question: "How did the caste system evolve over time?",
          optionA: "It became more flexible",
          optionB: "It became more rigid and birth-based",
          optionC: "It disappeared entirely",
          correctAnswer: "B) It became more rigid and birth-based",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which term was used to describe those engaged in 'lowly' or 'dirty' occupations?",
          optionA: "High-caste",
          optionB: "Low-caste",
          optionC: "Untouchables",
          correctAnswer: "B) Low-caste",
        },
        {
          question: "What did untouchability refer to in the caste system?",
          optionA: "The highest caste",
          optionB:
            "The practice of not allowing low-caste people to come into contact with high-caste people",
          optionC: "A group of social reformers",
          correctAnswer:
            "B) The practice of not allowing low-caste people to come into contact with high-caste people",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What were some consequences of the caste system, as mentioned in the text?",
          optionA: "National unity and progress",
          optionB: "Social reform and equality",
          optionC: "Fragmented society and underdevelopment",
          correctAnswer: "C) Fragmented society and underdevelopment",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What was Mahatma Gandhi's view on untouchability and the caste system?",
          optionA: "He believed in preserving the caste system",
          optionB: "He saw untouchability as a necessary evil",
          optionC:
            "He advocated for the eradication of untouchability and caste discrimination",
          correctAnswer:
            "C) He advocated for the eradication of untouchability and caste discrimination",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which social reformer is credited with incorporating provisions for reservation in the Constitution of India to uplift the Scheduled Castes?",
          optionA: "Sri Narayan Guru",
          optionB: "Periyar E.V. Ramaswamy",
          optionC: "Dr. Bhimrao Ramji Ambedkar",
          correctAnswer: "C) Dr. Bhimrao Ramji Ambedkar",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is one important implication of the social reform movement mentioned in the text?",
          optionA: "The decline of nationalism",
          optionB: "The rise of nationalism",
          optionC: "The spread of social evils",
          correctAnswer: "B) The rise of nationalism",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which laws passed by the British government aimed to address social customs and practices in India?",
          optionA: "Laws regarding dowry",
          optionB: "Laws regarding child marriages and widow remarriage",
          optionC: "Laws regarding religious freedom",
          correctAnswer:
            "B) Laws regarding child marriages and widow remarriage",
        },
],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [

  {
    "question": "In ancient Hindu society, there were four broad classes called Varnas: Brahmins (priests), Kshatriyas (warriors), Vaishyas (traders), and Shudras (workers). This classification was based on __________.",
    "optionA": "Wealth",
    "optionB": "Family lineage",
    "optionC": "Occupations",
    "correctAnswer": "Occupations"
  },
  {
    "question": "Over time, the caste system became rigid and birth-based. In the medieval period, most people adopted the occupation of their fathers; thus, the son of a Brahmin became a priest while that of a carpenter became __________ else but a carpenter.",
    "optionA": "A scholar",
    "optionB": "A trader",
    "optionC": "None",
    "correctAnswer": "None"
  },
  {
    "question": "The caste system resulted in many social evils, as follows: The caste system was a birth-based system in which a person was forced to adopt his parental occupation, and not any other of his choice. Thus, a washerman was not allowed to start a shop in provisions, or a low-caste scholar was not allowed to __________ and teach.",
    "optionA": "Travel",
    "optionB": "Study",
    "optionC": "Farm",
    "correctAnswer": "Study"
  },
  {
    "question": "Besides, some occupations came to be looked as superior and others as inferior. Those engaged in 'dirty' or 'lowly' occupations were termed 'low-caste'; for example, the workers who made shoes from the skin of dead animals came to be categorized as such. So was the case of several other occupations engaged in cleaning the drains, rowing the boats, washing dirty clothes, etc. In comparison, the people belonging to the first three classes: Brahmins, Kshatriyas, and Vaishyas came to be called __________ castes.",
    "optionA": "High",
    "optionB": "Middle",
    "optionC": "Low",
    "correctAnswer": "High"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most of the worker-class people were included in the category of the Shudras. They were treated as inferior and unclean, and were also imposed several restrictions. In many cases, they were treated as __________.",
    "optionA": "Scholars",
    "optionB": "Outcastes",
    "optionC": "Priests",
    "correctAnswer": "Outcastes"
  },
  {
    "question": "This caste system resulted into many social evils, as follows: In some cases, low-caste people were not allowed to live near the houses of high-caste people. Many high-caste people did not sell them commodities. The above restrictions resulted in __________.",
    "optionA": "Economic prosperity",
    "optionB": "National unity",
    "optionC": "Untouchability",
    "correctAnswer": "Untouchability"
  },
  {
    "question": "The caste system created several problems, many of these problems continue to plague the society even today. The important of which are as follows: The society was fragmented into high and low castes. All people were not treated as equal members of the society. A divided society naturally lacked __________.",
    "optionA": "Religious diversity",
    "optionB": "National unity",
    "optionC": "Economic prosperity",
    "correctAnswer": "National unity"
  },
  {
    "question": "Continuous wars depleted the population of the warrior class, but the low-caste people were not allowed to fight in the army. This weakened the __________.",
    "optionA": "Economy",
    "optionB": "Rulers",
    "optionC": "Religious institutions",
    "correctAnswer": "Rulers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Many talented people were wasted because merit was thought to be caste-based. The need for caste reform became obvious because of the above causes. It was felt that the society could not progress if all people were not allowed to __________.",
    "optionA": "Choose their caste",
    "optionB": "Prosper",
    "optionC": "Travel freely",
    "correctAnswer": "Prosper"
  },
  {
    "question": "An important implication of the social reform movement was the rise of __________. As people from different regions were able to mingle owing to newer means of transport, they started to identify themselves as Indians. This led to an intense freedom movement.",
    "optionA": "Economic prosperity",
    "optionB": "Nationalism",
    "optionC": "Untouchability",
    "correctAnswer": "Nationalism"
  }
]

    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) 
  activityData = 
  activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
  questions:

  {
    "question": "The caste system in ancient India was initially flexible and occupation-based.",
    "optionA": "True",
    "optionB": "False",
    "correctAnswer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "The caste system in ancient India became more rigid and birth-based over time.",
    "optionA": "True",
    "optionB": "False",
    "correctAnswer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the caste system, individuals were allowed to choose their own occupations, regardless of their family background.",
    "optionA": "True",
    "optionB": "False",
    "correctAnswer": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Untouchability was a practice where low-caste individuals were allowed to come into contact with high-caste individuals.",
    "optionA": "True",
    "optionB": "False",
    "correctAnswer": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "The caste system led to a more unified and equal society in ancient India.",
    "optionA": "True",
    "optionB": "False",
    "correctAnswer": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mahatma Gandhi advocated for the preservation of the caste system.",
    "optionA": "True",
    "optionB": "False",
    "correctAnswer": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dr. Bhimrao Ramji Ambedkar incorporated provisions for reservation in the Constitution of India to uplift the Scheduled Castes.",
    "optionA": "True",
    "optionB": "False",
    "correctAnswer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "The social reform movement in India had no impact on the rise of nationalism.",
    "optionA": "True",
    "optionB": "False",
    "correctAnswer": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "The caste system is based on the principles of natural justice and equality.",
    "optionA": "True",
    "optionB": "False",
    "correctAnswer": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Periyar E.V. Ramaswamy fought for the preservation of the caste system in Hindu society.",
    "optionA": "True",
    "optionB": "False",
    "correctAnswer": "False"
  }
]



export var activityData;
